Guide to the Chard Powers Smith Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1901-1978; Series I; 21.27; (51 boxes)
  - General Correspondence, 1910-1978
    - The Waterbury Hospital, 1953 August 17 (Box 37, Folder 1570)
      See also: United States. Marine Corps
    - Watertown Daily Times, 1941 September 23 (Box 37, Folder 1571)
    - Watson, Evelyn, 1931, undated (Box 37, Folder 1572)
    - Webb, Kenneth and Susan, 1968-1972 (Box 37, Folder 1573)
    - Weber, Carl J., 1965 (Box 37, Folder 1574)
    - Weber, William, 1939-1941 (Box 37, Folder 1575)
      See also: Perkins, Max
    - Weigand, James, 1974 February 1 (Box 37, Folder 1576)
    - Welch, Marie de L., undated (Box 37, Folder 1577)
    - Weldon, Robert, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 1578)
    - Wells, Winifred, 1932-1936 (Box 37, Folder 1579)
    - Wellesley College, 1949-1950 (Box 37, Folder 1580)
    - Wesleyan University, 1942 June 18 (Box 38, Folder 1581)
    - Wesleyan University Press, 1960-1969 (Box 38, Folder 1582)
    - West Cornwall Public Library, 1941 October 20 (Box 38, Folder 1583)
    - West Stockbridge Public Library, 1944-1946 (Box 38, Folder 1584)
    - Westbrook, Perry, 1964 June 10 (Box 38, Folder 1585)
    - Westermann, Edward and Esther, 1952-1954 (Box 38, Folder 1586)
    - Whalen, John, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 1587)
    - Whalen, Margaret, undated (Box 38, Folder 1588)
    - Whalen, Peter, 1965 December 8 (Box 38, Folder 1589)
    - Wheeler, Jo Ann, 1933 December 16 (Box 38, Folder 1590)
    - Wheeler, Paul M., 1947-1948 (Box 38, Folder 1591)
    - Wheeler, Sarah C., 1939 November 11 (Box 38, Folder 1592)
    - Wheelock, John Hall, 1933-1973 (Box 38, Folder 1593-1594)
    - Whelan, Kenneth Ellsworth, 1934-1936 (Box 38, Folder 1595)
    - White, Grace H., 1935 (Box 38, Folder 1596)
    - White, Weld & Co., 1969 October 3 (Box 38, Folder 1597)
    - Whittlesey, 1950 (Box 38, Folder 1598)
    - Who's Who in America, 1949-1974 (Box 38, Folder 1599)
    - Who's Who in the Western Hemisphere, 1943 September 14 (Box 38, Folder 1600)
    - Wickersham, George W., 1935 (Box 38, Folder 1601)
    - Wickham, Peter, 1963 October 23 (Box 38, Folder 1602)
    - Widdemer, Margaret, 1949-1962 (Box 38, Folder 1603)
    - Wilbur, Richard, 1967-1971 (Box 38, Folder 1604)
    - Wilder, Harry, 1911 (Box 38, Folder 1605)
    - Wilder, James H., 1829 April 29 (Box 38, Folder 1606)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1959-1961 (Box 38, Folder 1607)
    - Willets, Myrtle Stowe, 1946 June 23 (Box 38, Folder 1608)
    - William Sloane Associates, Inc., 1947-1964 (Box 38, Folder 1609)
    - Williams College, 1973 March 26 (Box 38, Folder 1610)
    - Williams, J. Harold, 1951 (Box 38, Folder 1611)
    - Williams, Jean, 1960-1974 (Box 38, Folder 1612)
    - Williams, Marshall H., 1965-1974 (Box 38, Folder 1613)
    - Williams, Oscar, 1940 September 25 (Box 38, Folder 1614)
    - Williams, Schafer, 1967-1969 (Box 38, Folder 1615)
    - Williams, Stanley, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 1616)
    - Williams, Suzie, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 1617)
    - Wilmington College, 1971-1972 (Box 38, Folder 1618)
    - Wilmot, Jack, 1934 (Box 38, Folder 1619)
    - Wilson College, 1968-1973 (Box 38, Folder 1620)
    - Wilson, Marjorie, 1926 June 16 (Box 38, Folder 1621)
    - Wilson, William and Frieda, undated (Box 38, Folder 1622)
    - Wing, Willis Kingsley, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 1623)
    - Winslow, Richard, 1969 August 11 (Box 38, Folder 1624)
    - Winter, Patricia Ignacious, 1936 September 18 (Box 38, Folder 1625)
    - Winterfield, Peggy H., 1966-1967 (Box 38, Folder 1626)
    - Wise, Elizabeth Anderson, 1935 (Box 38, Folder 1627)
    - Witten, Gene and Anita, 1963-1967 (Box 38, Folder 1628)
    - Wolcott and Litchfield Circulating Library Association, 1942 December 5 (Box 38, Folder 1629)
    - Wolf, Anton, 1952 (Box 38, Folder 1630)
    - Wolf, Lisa, 1925 June 4 (Box 38, Folder 1631)
    - The Woman's Club of Chatham, Chatham (New Jersey), undated (Box 38, Folder 1632)
    - The Woman's Forum, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 1633)
    - Woman's Roosevelt Memorial Association, 1928 (Box 38, Folder 1634)
    - Wood, Louise H., 1965 June 18 (Box 38, Folder 1635)
    - Woodland California Draft Board, 1972 July 5 (Box 38, Folder 1636)
    - Woodruff, Mary R., undated (Box 38, Folder 1637)
    - World Magazine, 1973 (Box 38, Folder 1638)
    - Worthington, William, 1946 July 23 (Box 38, Folder 1639)
    - Wreisel, Marie, undated (Box 38, Folder 1640)
    - Wright, Ellen, 1965, undated (Box 38, Folder 1641)
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1941 August 5 (Box 38, Folder 1642)
    - Wright, Paul H., 1940 June 3 (Box 38, Folder 1643)
    - Writers' War Board, 1943 March 4 (Box 38, Folder 1644)
    - Wylie, Phillip, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 1645)
    - Wyman, Janet, 1957 December 10 (Box 38, Folder 1646)
    - Yaddo, 1956-1957 (Box 39, Folder 1647)
    - The Yale Alumni Weekly, 1931 January 23 (Box 39, Folder 1648)
    - Yale Library Association, 1960 November 14 (Box 39, Folder 1649)
    - The Yale Review, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 1650)
    - Yale University, 1915-1970 (Box 39, Folder 1651)
    - Yale University. Department of History, 1948 July 16 (Box 39, Folder 1652)
    - Yale University. Office of the Provost, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 1653)
    - Yale University Library, 1938-1973 (Box 39, Folder 1654-1655)
    - Yale University Press, 1925-1971 (Box 39, Folder 1656)
    - Yankee, Inc., 1937-1968 (Box 39, Folder 1657)
    - Yoken, Melvin B., 1970-1973 (Box 39, Folder 1658)
    - Yost, Gertrude A., 1936, undated (Box 39, Folder 1659)
    - Young, Nancy, 1948 August 7 (Box 39, Folder 1660)
    - Young, Stanley, 1948 April 9 (Box 39, Folder 1661)
    - Youngburt, John and June, 1937, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 1662)
    - Youngs, Robert Wells, 1943 October 20 (Box 39, Folder 1663)
    - Yutzler, F., 1948 September 17 (Box 39, Folder 1664)
    - Zdanowicz, Frederica, 1973 January 25 (Box 39, Folder 1665)
    - Zetek, James, undated (Box 39, Folder 1666)
    - Christmas cards, 1927 (Box 39, Folder 1667)
    - Empty envelopes, 1890-1965, undated (Box 39, Folder 1668)
    - Blank postcards, undated (Box 39, Folder 1669)
    - First names only, 1910-1975 (Box 40, Folder 1670-1698)
    - Unidentified, 1929-1965, undated (Box 40, Folder 1699)
  - Family Correspondence, 1901-1977
    - Clark, Alice, 1959, undated (Box 41, Folder 1700)
    - Clark, Arnold, 1958-1968 (Box 41, Folder 1701-1704)
    - Clark, Nathaniel F., 1966-1970 (Box 41, Folder 1705-1707)
      See also: Woodland California Draft Board
    - Clark, Paul Franklin, 1957-1972 (Box 41, Folder 1708-1713)
    - Clark, Sarah Bancroft, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 1714)
    - "Family", 1921 (Box 41, Folder 1715)
    - Gallup, Elizabeth Chard Smith, 1915-1931 (Box 41, Folder 1716)
    - Jorgensen, Pamela A., 1967-1971 (Box 41, Folder 1717)
    - Jorgensen, Ric, 1961-1972 (Box 41, Folder 1718)
    - Jorgensen, Robert and Rebecca, 1959-1972 (Box 41, Folder 1719-1723)
    - Lamon, Alice M., 1951 February 5 (Box 41, Folder 1724)
    - Marsh, Frederick, 1935, undated (Box 41, Folder 1725)
    - McCabe, Gillie, 1921-1928 (Box 41, Folder 1726)
    - McGrane, Nancy, undated (Box 41, Folder 1727)
    - Powers, Lorinda L., 1901-1910 (Box 41, Folder 1728-1732)
    - Powers, Lorinda L., 1910-1913 (Box 42, Folder 1733-1745)
    - Powers, Lorinda L., 1914-1919 (Box 43, Folder 1746-1761)
    - Powers, Lorinda L., 1920-1921, undated (Box 44, Folder 1762-1766)
    - Robinson, Mabel, 1941-1950, undated (Box 44, Folder 1767)
    - Smith, Alice Lamon Powers, 1882-1906, undated (Box 44, Folder 1768)
    - Smith, Carey, 1970-1973, undated (Box 44, Folder 1769)
    - Smith, Chard Powers Jr., 1954-1974, undated (Box 44, Folder 1770-1775)
    - Smith, Mary Elizabeth ("Dusty"), 1950-1974, undated (Box 44, Folder 1776)
    - Smith, Edward North, 1909-1923, undated (Box 44, Folder 1777-1781)
    - Smith, Eunice Clark, 1929-1977, undated (Box 45, Folder 1782-1787)
    - Smith, Marion Ward, 1939-1955 (Box 45, Folder 1788-1789)
    - Smith, Nannette, 1944-1973 (Box 45, Folder 1790-1798)
    - Smith, Olive Cary Macdonald, 1919-1924 (Box 46, Folder 1799-1802)
    - Smith, Sarah, 1967-1973, undated (Box 46, Folder 1803)
    - Smith, Trem, 1963-1970, undated (Box 46, Folder 1804)
    - Stanley, Eamon, 1971-1973, undated (Box 46, Folder 1805)
    - Stanley, Marion Kendall Smith, 1954-1973, undated (Box 46, Folder 1806-1809)
    - Stanley, William Clinton Jr., 1965, undated (Box 46, Folder 1810)
    - Walter, Gladys, 1958-1965 (Box 46, Folder 1811)
    - ----, Carrie, 1925 (Box 46, Folder 1812)
    - ----, Josephine, 1926 (Box 46, Folder 1813)
    - ----, Laura, undated (Box 46, Folder 1814)
    - ----, Lydia, 1910-1911 (Box 46, Folder 1815)
    - ----, Merton, undated (Box 46, Folder 1816)
    - ----, Ruth, undated (Box 46, Folder 1817)
    - Unidentified family, undated (Box 46, Folder 1818)
  - Third Party Correspondence, undated
    - Bond, W. H. to Hart, A. L., 1963 June 6 (Box 47, Folder 1819)
    - Canby, Henry to Draper, Charles I. (carbon), 1942 June 18 (Box 47, Folder 1820)
    - Clarkie to Jean Crawford, 1945 October 18 (Box 47, Folder 1821)
    - Collins, Mark to Edwards, Sir ----, 1927 May 24 (Box 47, Folder 1822)
    - Corey, Ruth Lechlitner to Norman Cousins, 1973 January 29 (Box 47, Folder 1823)
    - Crain, Henry M. to Crain, Annie Laurie, 1943-1944 (Box 47, Folder 1824)
    - Crossman, Edgar, 1939 (Box 47, Folder 1825-1829)
    - Dillon, George to Jones, Miss ----, undated (Box 47, Folder 1830)
    - Dulles, ---- (addressed to), undated (Box 47, Folder 1831)
    - Elder, Robert H. to Charles Scribners and Sons, 1940 November 28 (Box 47, Folder 1832)
    - Fackenthal, Frank D. to Peter Pauper Press, 1936 October 28 (Box 47, Folder 1833)
    - Flanigan, Rose to Thorpe, Marjorie, 1966 June 2 (Box 47, Folder 1834)
    - Franchere, Hoyt to MacMillan Co., 1931, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 1835)
    - Gardner, ---- to Janet, 1926 July 15 (Box 47, Folder 1836)
    - Gilchrist, Marie to Goldbeck, Eva, 1928 July 9 (Box 47, Folder 1837)
    - Gregory, William K., 1927-1929 (Box 47, Folder 1838)
    - Hargrave, Thomas Jean to Hunting, Maro S., 1935 October 16 (Box 47, Folder 1839)
    - Harrington, Donald to Munson, Gorham, 1955 February 10 (Box 47, Folder 1840)
    - Helfrich, R. to Crossman, Edgar, 1939 February 15 (Box 47, Folder 1841)
    - Hopkins, Herman to Gallup, Mrs. ----, undated (Box 47, Folder 1842)
    - Hurter, Janet, 1919-1921 (Box 47, Folder 1843)
    - Jackson, William A. to MacMillan Co. (photocopies), 1963 (Box 47, Folder 1844)
    - Kent, Sarah to Thorpe, Marjorie, undated (Box 47, Folder 1845)
    - The Latin Quarterly (Widen, Ruth) to Frost, Frances, 1933 November 20 (Box 47, Folder 1846)
    - Lemay, Harding to Balassa, Mrs. ----, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 1847)
    - Ottmiller, John H. to Faulder, Ann, 1965 July 23 (Box 47, Folder 1848)
    - Perry, Bernard to Hart, A. L., 1973 September 19 (Box 47, Folder 1849)
    - Rorty, James, 1964-1965, undated (Box 47, Folder 1850)
    - Scoville, Louise Armstrong to Choate, Mabel, 1943 March 1 (Box 47, Folder 1851)
    - Sitwell, Evelyn to Sitwell, Edith, 1926 June 2 (Box 47, Folder 1852)
    - Staley, Harry to Grimes, William and Janet, 1965 October 14 (Box 47, Folder 1853)
    - Thorpe, Marjorie to and from Blake, Whitney, 1973 August 8 (Box 47, Folder 1854)
    - Viereck, Peter to Clark McCutcheon, 1967 February 18 (Box 47, Folder 1855)
    - Yale Univeristy Press (Blake, Whitney) to Hart, A. L., 1974 January 11 (Box 47, Folder 1856)
    - Young, Robert to Hare, Montgomery, 1973 February 1 (Box 47, Folder 1857)
    - Unidentified, 1926 (Box 47, Folder 1858)
  - Correspondence Photocopies, undated
    - A-F, undated (Box 48, Folder 1859-1874)
    - G-M, undated (Box 49, Folder 1875-1888)
    - N-V, undated (Box 50, Folder 1889-1905)
    - W-Z, unsorted, undated (Box 51, Folder 1906-1915)
- Writings, circa 1922-1956, undated; Series II; 50.88; (124 boxes)
  Series II. Writings contains notes, outlines, drafts, and proofs documenting Smith's writing career from his first volume of poetry, Along the Wind, published by Yale University Press in 1925, through an extensive autobiography that he worked on towards the end of his life. Most drafts are heavily annotated, and some are accompanied by research materials and reviews. Other research material can be found in Series I. Correspondence, and in Series V. Subject Files and Printed Material. Contracts and royalty statements can be found in Series III. Personal Papers.
  The series is organized into four subseries: Prose, Poetry, Drama, and Writings of Others. Each subseries, excluding Writings of Others, is arranged alphabetically by title of the work, or by format for shorter works. The Writings of Others subseries is further divided by genre, and the writings are listed alphabetically by author.
  - Prose, 1939-1949, undated
    - Annals of the Poets, undated
      - Holograph drafts, undated (Box 52, Folder 1916-1927)
      - Holograph drafts and typescript penultimate draft, corrected, undated (Box 53, Folder 1928-1938)
      - Holograph and typescript drafts, corrected, undated (Box 54, Folder 1939-1956)
    - Artillery of Time, 1939, undated
      - Notes and very early drafts, undated (Box 55, Folder 1957-2008)
      - Discards, undated (Box 56, Folder 2009-2046)
      - Notes and sources, drafts and discards, undated (Box 57, Folder 2047-2099)
      - Portions cut, undated (Box 58, Folder 2100-2122)
      - Part III early draft, undated (Box 59, Folder 2123-2151)
      - Part III complete manuscript, undated (Box 60, Folder 2152-2172)
      - Part IV, undated (Box 61, Folder 2173-2190)
      - Typescript carbon, manuscript draft (corrected), typescript draft carbon (corrected), and typescript original (corrected), undated (Box 62, Folder 2191-2241)
      - Typescript draft (heavily corrected), undated (Box 63, Folder 2242-2273)
      - Typescript draft (heavily corrected), undated (Box 64, Folder 2274-2308)
      - Typescript final draft, undated (Box 65, Folder 2309-2362)
      - Typescript final draft, undated (Box 66, Folder 2363-2416)
      - Printed sources and review blurbs, undated (Box 67, Folder 2417-2444)
        Includes 1939 edition annotated by author.
    - Autobiography, undated
      - Notes, undated (Box 68, Folder 2445-2468)
      - Preface, typescript draft corrected, undated (Box 69, Folder 2469-2480)
      - Part I, early typescript drafts corrected, undated (Box 70, Folder 2481-2494)
      - Part I, typescript draft corrected, undated (Box 71, Folder 2495-2515)
      - Part I, typescript draft corrected, undated (Box 72, Folder 2516-2542)
      - Part I, late typescript draft corrected, undated (Box 73, Folder 2543-2582)
      - Part I, printed sources, undated (Box 74, Folder 2583-2588)
      - Part II, holograph and typescript notes and printed sources, undated (Box 75, Folder 2589-2608)
      - Part II, early typescript drafts corrected, undated (Box 76, Folder 2609-2634)
      - Part II, typescript carbon drafts, undated (Box 77, Folder 2635-2653)
      - Part III, holograph and typescript notes and printed sources, undated (Box 78, Folder 2654-2693)
      - Part III, printed sources, undated (Box 79, Folder 2694-2706)
      - Part III, printed sources, undated (Box 80, Folder 2707-2711)
      - Part III, early typescript drafts corrected, undated (Box 81, Folder 2712-2750)
      - Part III, Books 1 and 2, typescript draft and typescript carbon draft, undated (Box 82, Folder 2751-2806)
      - Part IV, holograph and typescript notes and printed sources, undated (Box 83, Folder 2807-2837)
      - Part IV, Books 1 and 2, typescript drafts, undated (Box 84, Folder 2838-2873)
      - Part IV, typescript drafts corrected, undated (Box 85, Folder 2874-2916)
      - Part V, holograph and typescript notes, undated (Box 86, Folder 2917-2952)
      - Part V, printed sources, undated (Box 87, Folder 2953-2978)
      - Part VI, holograph and typescript notes and printed sources, undated (Box 88, Folder 2979-3025)
      - Part VI, printed sources, undated (Box 89, Folder 3026-3062)
      - Part VII, holograph and typescript notes and printed sources, undated (Box 90, Folder 3063-3088)
    - "Bird Migration," holograph notes and typescript, undated (Box 91, Folder 3089-3092)
    - "The Chardon Street Convention," M.A. Thesis, holograph notes and tyypescript drafts, 1949 (Box 91, Folder 3093-3100)
    - "Concerning Love", undated (Box 92, Folder 3101-3111)
    - "Concerning Paradise", undated
      - Typescript draft corrected, undated (Box 93, Folder 3112-3142)
      - Book I, typescript draft, undated (Box 94, Folder 3143-3158)
      - Book II, typescript draft and holograph notes, undated (Box 95, Folder 3159-3196)
      - Book I, typescript carbon, undated (Box 96, Folder 3197-3241)
      - Book II, typescript carbon, undated (Box 97, Folder 3242-3278)
    - "Days of Grace," typescript draft, undated (Box 98, Folder 3279-3281)
    - Death Falls, undated
      - Book I, typescript draft corrected, undated (Box 99, Folder 3282-3319)
      - Book II, typescript draft corrected, undated (Box 100, Folder 3320-3351)
      - Book III, typescript draft corrected, undated (Box 101, Folder 3352-3389)
    - "Distributist-Agrarian Movement," monograph and typescript drafts and notes, undated (Box 102, Folder 3390-3408)
    - "The Equal Man," typescript draft corrected, undated (Box 103, Folder 3409-3413)
    - Essays, undated (Box 104, Folder 3414-3443)
    - Essays, undated (Box 105, Folder 3444-3476)
    - Essays, undated (Box 106, Folder 3477-3515)
    - Essays, undated (Box 107, Folder 3516-3553)
    - Essays, undated (Box 108, Folder 3554-3561)
    - "Evolution Epic," typescript, undated (Box 109, Folder 3562-3573)
    - "Fran's Way," typescript, undated (Box 110, Folder 3574-3577)
    - "Gettysburg Gita," typescript, undated (Box 110, Folder 3578-3589)
    - Hamilton, holograph draft, undated (Box 111, Folder 3590-3601)
    - He's in the Artillery Now, holograph and typescript outline and drafts, undated (Box 112, Folder 3602-3625)
    - The Housatonic: Puritan River, undated
      - Typescript and manuscript notes, undated (Box 113, Folder 3626-3665)
      - Notes and printed sources, undated (Box 114, Folder 3666-3670)
      - Early draft, typescript and manuscript, undated (Box 115, Folder 3671-3697)
      - Early drafts, typescript, manuscript and discards, undated (Box 116, Folder 3698-3733)
      - Penultimate manuscript, undated (Box 117, Folder 3734-3766)
    - John Sterling, Bookseller, typescript drafts and proofs, undated (Box 118, Folder 3767-3769)
    - Ladies Day, 1941, undated
      - Notes and early drafts, undated (Box 119, Folder 3770-3812)
      - Penultimate draft, undated (Box 120, Folder 3813-3864)
      - Final typescript draft, undated (Box 121, Folder 3865-3903)
      - Published volume annotated by author, with inserts and review blurbs, 1941 (Box 122, Folder 3904-3905)
      - Proofs, undated
    - Lecture notes, undated (Box 123, Folder 3906-3910)
    - Lecture notes, undated (Box 124, Folder 3911-3913)
    - Letters to the Editor, undated (Box 125, Folder 3914-3917)
    - "Mainstream or Eddy??", undated (Box 125, Folder 3918-3919)
    - "The Old Hebrew-Xian Myth", undated (Box 125, Folder 3920-3927)
    - One Life to Give, notes, outlines and drafts, undated (Box 126, Folder 3928-3936)
    - Pattern and Variation in Poetry, undated
      - Drafts, undated (Box 127, Folder 3937-3967)
      - Typescript draft, corrected, undated (Box 128, Folder 3968-3977)
      - Drafts and proofs, undated (Box 129, Folder 3978-3992)
      - Corrected proofs, photocopies, undated (Box 130, Folder 3993-3995)
    - "Plain Humor" drafts, undated (Box 131, Folder 3996-4001)
    - Poets of the Twenties, undated
      - Typescript and manuscript drafts, undated (Box 132, Folder 4002-4024)
      - Typescript and manuscript drafts, undated (Box 133, Folder 4025-4040)
      - Proofs, undated
        Existence and Location of Originals
        Stored in: Oversize Poets of the Twenties, proofs (in Series II. Writings)
    - "The Polis, Athenian and Yankee" notes and drafts, undated (Box 134, Folder 4041-4047)
    - "Quakers", undated
      - Manuscript and typescript drafts and notes, undated (Box 135, Folder 4048-4092)
      - Manuscript and typescript drafts and notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 4093-4155)
    - "Robinson and Puritanism", undated
      - Typescript drafts, undated (Box 137, Folder 4156-4174)
      - Typescript drafts and carbons, undated (Box 138, Folder 4175-4202)
    - Speech notes, undated (Box 139, Folder 4203-4223)
    - Speech notes, undated (Box 140, Folder 4224-4237)
    - "Spike's OK", undated
      - Typescript draft, undated (Box 141, Folder 4238-4296)
      - Notes and drafts, undated (Box 142, Folder 4297-4332)
      - Typescript drafts, undated (Box 143, Folder 4333-4376)
    - "The Theorist" typescript, undated (Box 144, Folder 4377-4383)
    - "Tom and Bobby" typescript, undated (Box 144, Folder 4384-4385)
    - "Turn Off the Dial" typescript, undated (Box 144, Folder 4386-4413)
    - Where the Light Falls: a portrait of Edwin Arlington Robinson, undated
      - Notes and early drafts, undated (Box 145, Folder 4414-4472)
      - Typescript drafts, undated (Box 146, Folder 4473-4487)
      - Typescript drafts, undated (Box 147, Folder 4488-4509)
      - Typescript drafts, undated (Box 148, Folder 4510-4534)
      - Typescript drafts, undated (Box 149, Folder 4535-4584)
      - Final typescript, undated (Box 150, Folder 4585-4601)
      - Setting typescript and review blurbs, undated (Box 151, Folder 4602-4646)
    - Yankees and God, undated
      - Notes, undated (Box 152, Folder 4647-4667)
      - Printed sources, undated (Box 153, Folder 4668-4680)
      - Ronsheim index and notes, undated (Box 154, Folder 4681-4691)
      - Part I notes and drafts, undated (Box 155, Folder 4692-4707)
      - Part II notes and drafts, undated (Box 156, Folder 4708-4718)
      - Part II notes and drafts, undated (Box 157, Folder 4719-4729)
      - Part III notes and drafts, undated (Box 158, Folder 4730-4742)
      - Part III notes and drafts, undated (Box 159, Folder 4743-4759)
    - Young Lathrop Samson, circa 1948, undated
      - Typescript drafts, [1948?] (Box 160, Folder 4760-4774)
      - Typescript drafts, undated (Box 161, Folder 4775-4828)
      - Penultimate draft typescript, 1948 (Box 162, Folder 4829-4856)
      - Penultimate draft carbons, 1948 (Box 163, Folder 4857-4918)
      - Ultimate draft carbons, circa 1948 (Box 164, Folder 4919-4975)
    - Unidentified prose writings and notes, undated (Box 165, Folder 4976-5126)
  - Poetry, 1928-1956, undated
    - Along the Wind, drafts and proofs, circa 1925 (Box 166, Folder 5127-5147)
    - Lyric poetry drafts, 1928-1941 (Box 167, Folder 5148-5176)
    - Lyric poetry drafts and discards, 1942-1956 (Box 168, Folder 5177-5194)
    - The Peace We Left, undated (Box 169, Folder 5195-5197)
    - Prelude to Man, undated
      - Notes and drafts, undated (Box 170, Folder 5198-5282)
        Also stored in Oversize Prelude to Man, notes and drafts (in Series II. Writings)
      - Epic Preface, drafts and notes, undated (Box 170, Folder 5283-5290)
      - Early manuscript, undated (Box 171, Folder 5291)
      - Outline manuscript draft, undated (Box 172, Folder 5292)
      - "Pan the Body" typescript drafts, undated (Box 172, Folder 5293-5298)
      - "Jehova the Mind" typescript drafts, undated (Box 172, Folder 5299-5310)
      - "Brahma the Spirit" typescript drafts, undated (Box 172, Folder 5311-5314)
      - Epilogue typescript draft, undated (Box 172, Folder 5315)
      - Unidentified typescripts and related material, undated (Box 172, Folder 5316-5335)
      - Proofs, undated
    - Unidentified poetry, undated (Box 173, Folder 5336-5457)
    - Unidentified poetry, undated (Box 174, Folder 5458-5650)
  - Drama, circa 1922-1923, undated